DAMILOLA JERUGBA

hello@damiisdandv.com | github.com/damiisdandv | damiisdandv.com | LinkedIn

Software Engineer

Software Engineer with 3+ years of full-stack web development experience specializing in ReactJS, Typescript, NodeJS, Python, Postgresql, and MongoDB. A Technical writer interested in learning and documenting topics on programming languages, algorithms, and developer tooling.

Languages and Skills

Javascript, Typescript, React, Lit, NodeJS, Python, Jest, Cypress, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Docker, CI/CD, Serverless, DevOps, System Design, Git & Agile

Work Experience

Reddit: Software Developer | Remote | 02/2023 - 12/2023

- Built complex UIs used by thousands of advertisers and millions of Reddit users with React, Web components, and Typescript, this helped increase advertiser acquisition, activation and retention by 23%.
- Architected front end design and backend handoff for customer facing features on the Reddit Ads site.
- Collaborated with other developers in meeting consumers needs and targets by increasing conversion rate for Reddit Ads and increasing Advertiser count.
- Implemented tests and code coverage on UI components and functionality using Jest, Playwright, and custom testing tools.

Aerial: Software Developer | Remote | 12/2022 - 02/2023

- Builts full stack applications with tRPC, Nextjs and MongoDB to help customers manage and organize their legal papers and documents
- Contributed to the open-source library ts-mongo to add property type definition for string manipulations, which led to be code readability and security
- Worked closely with seasoned developers to maintain and improve the performance and security of mongoDB database by moving the permissions logic to the ORM level.

OpenSpec: Software Developer | Remote | 04/2022 - 09/2022

- Built full stack application implementing Machine Learning algorithms to aid Product Managers write better Product requirements by generating User Stories, Scenarios, and Edge Cases utilizing OpenAI, React, Prisma & NodeJS.
- Developed End-to-End (E2E) Tests to improve the correctness and health of the entirety of the codebase.
- Prepared software development strategies including test-driven development & constant integration increasing code coverage by 30%.
- Applied performance improvement techniques to global state management which led to a 40% increase in performance and customer satisfaction.

Brimble: Lead Frontend Developer | Remote | 09/2021 - 03/2022

- Implemented technologies such as Progressive Web Application (PWA) to aid website load times and better Search Engine Optimization (SEO) increasing conversion rates by 55%.
- Migrated 3,000+ lines of code in codebase from Vue to React, while implementing view model patterns to improve code maintainability and readability.
- Wrote, Edited & Published 5+ technical articles at <u>DEV.to</u>

Education

DAMILOLA JERUGBA

hello@damiisdandv.com | github.com/damiisdandv | damiisdandv.com | LinkedIn

Projects and Achievements

- <u>ts-mongo</u> (Typescript & MongoDB)
 - Contributed to ts-mongo, an open source library by adding strict type definitions to MongoDB
- <u>damiisdandy/use-pagination</u> (ReactJS & Typescript)
 - A personal library with 70+ Github stars to help with pagination in React by building a custom usePagination hook
- <u>Playlist Converter</u> (Python & React)
 - Search/convert playlists from one streaming platform to another with the use of React and FastAPI
- Technical Writer
 - I have over 30,000 readers on Dev.to and won best React article of the week